CHRIS FISHER

Senior Software Engineer

254-258-9604 | clfshr@gmail.com | chrsfshr.com

CAREER SUMMARY:

Solution-oriented problem solver with 10 years of experience building and maintaining web application software. Highly skilled in communication, between the technical disciplines of design and development. Solving challenges at every touch point in a project's journey, from ideation to technical application.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

IBM Quantum

Senior Software Engineer | Nov 2018 - Present

- Led development for the IBM Quantum Experience team in building the first and only flagship marketing web application for IBM Quantum.
- Advised and collaborated with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, product managers and stakeholders on technical application.
- Helped solidify and grow IBM Quantum's brand recognition in organic SEO growth for keywords to #1 on Google.
- Worked with a variety of different languages and frameworks: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue, Node.js, SASS, Strapi, Directus.

IBM Watson Education

Software Developer | April 2016 - Nov 2018

- Worked in a team of 3 developers to engineer and implement IBM's first industry application using AI (Watson) specific to helping teachers manage their classrooms.
- Engineered and maintained major features and UI components for 2 major market releases.
- Proposed and implemented scalable solutions to address application accessibility and inclusion from development to design.
- Worked with a variety of different languages and frameworks: JavaScript, Angular, Node.is, SASS

Charity Dynamics

Associate Web Developer | February 2014 - May 2016

World Video Bible School (WVBS)

Web Developer & Tech Support | April 2013 - Jan 2014

Texas Department of Family and Protective Services

Systems Support Specialist III | September 2008 - March 2013

SKILLS:

- Programming Languages: JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS/Sass
- Libraries & Frameworks: React, Vue, Angular, ¡Query, Node.js, Gatsby
- Design/Tools: Sketch, Figma, Invision, Mural, Git, Webpack, Docker

EDUCATION: